<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
    The Making EHR Data More Available for Research and Public Health (MedMorph) project seeks to advance public health and patient-centered outcomes 
    by using emerging health data and exchange standards, such as Health Level 7 (HL7) Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources (FHIR) and 
    Clinical Quality Language (CQL), to develop and implement an interoperable solution that will enable access to clinical data. 
    The MedMorph project fits within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) strategic imperative of transforming how data is collected, 
    used, and shared through modern Information Technology (IT) capabilities to save lives and improve health.  
    The MedMorph project is funded by the Health and Human Services (HHS) Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation (ASPE) 
    Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Trust Fund (PCORTF) and executed by the Center for Surveillance, Epidemiology, and Laboratory Services (CSELS) 
    to advance research and public health goals.
    </p>
    <p>
	The project aims to leverage the maturation of standards and requirements for certification of health information technology by the 
	Office of the National Coordinator for Health IT (ONC) that underpin many EHRs. 
	Examples such as Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources (FHIR), the ONC 2015 Edition Common Clinical Data Set (CCDS), 
	2015 Edition Cures Update - United States Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Version 1, February 2020 and 
	standardized application programming interfaces (API) for patient services have created a health IT environment that is 
	ripe for developing standards based scalable and extensible solutions to overcome interoperability challenges. 
    </p>
    
    <p>
    The MedMorph project will create fully modeled use cases across three distinct areas; hepatitis C virus (HCV), 
    cancer reporting and health care surveys to inform the design of a scalable and extensible reference architecture 
    to facilitate data exchange for both key patient-centered research questions and public health surveillance system requirements.
    For more detailed explanation on the reference architecture refer to <a href="background.html">Implementation Guide Overview</a>.
    </p>
	
	<a name="technical"> </a>
	<h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <p>
    The main sections of this IG are:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="background.html">Implementation Guide Overview</a> - provides context for the implementation guide and information that implementers should be
      familiar with before reading the remainder of the IG.  
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="usecases.html">Use Cases</a> - describes the business need, actors, and workflows for the IG.  
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="spec.html">Detailed Specification</a> - defines the specific conformance requirements for systems wishing to conform to actors specified in the IG.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Useful Downloads</a> - provides the ability to download a copy of the entire implementation guide, artifact definitions, or examples.
    </li>
  </ul>
</div>
